Welcome into the lounge presented by
DraftKings. I'm Garrett Downing joined
by Clifton Brown. We are here at the NFL
owners meetings in Phoenix, Arizona. And
Cliff, this is a big important week uh
for the Ravens and for the league as a
whole. What has stood out to you about
this week?
>> Well, on one side you have football work
and obviously personnel and you know
what teams and coaches, owners, general
managers are thinking about and then
there's the business side of the sport.
lot of business is conducted here. NFL
business, club business. So, we see both
sides of those things getting
accomplished here.
>> Yeah, no doubt. Well, one person who is
highly involved in all of that is Ravens
team president Sashi Brown. I sat down
with him for an interview to talk about
what are the top priorities for the
Ravens and it's been a big offseason uh
here in Baltimore. So, uh, talk with
Sashi about this off seasonason and also
what he sees ahead for the Ravens.
>> Ravens fans, I'm excited to sit down
with team president Sashi Brown here at
the NFL owners meetings. Sashi, thank
you so much for the time.
>> Good to be with you. How you doing?
>> I'm doing great.
>> Good.
>> It's a it's a busy week and a busy off
season for the Ravens. It's been a off
season of change.
>> It has been
>> for the Ravens with Jesse Mentor coming
in as the head coach. What has stood out
to you about this entire process getting
to the point where we are today where
Jesse's leading this this new evolution
of the Ravens?
>> Strength in our leadership starting with
Steve, Eric, Azie, myself, uh, Dick, and
then bringing Jesse into that group. And
then a really strong staff underneath
all of us, you know, to help support us
through that process and decisions. And
then just I think the other thing that I
reflect on is organizationally just how
rooted in our kind of values and our
system and our way that we really are.
So not easy. John was like a brother to
all of us. Still is. Uh and even though
I haven't seen him, I'm going to find
him here in a little bit. And uh he'll
knuckle my head, I'll knuckle his head.
But, um, you know, Jesse coming right
into our family, uh, you know, here at
the Ravens and and, you know, has hit
the ground running, put together a great
staff, uh, but everybody working really
well together and really anchored by our
values.
>> Something that stands out to me about
Jesse, and he mentioned this from his
very first day on the job set, he wants
to be a connector. He wants to bring
people together. How have you seen him
go about that? Yeah, a couple things is
I think, you know, the way that he's
worked right off the bat with Eric, um
we'll get a chance to to do it in in
real form as we get deeper into draft
meetings. Uh but his engagement with
players, the way he treats people around
the building, uh and the messages that
he's sending, the way he's
communicating, uh he's a great partner,
great teammate. I look forward to
working with him for a long time. So,
there's a lot of things on the Ravens
plate on the football field, off the
football field. For you, when you look
at the big picture of the organization,
what do you see as the top
organizational priorities right now?
>> Winning.
>> Always number one.
>> Winning is always number one. Uh we got
to get back on top of this division, and
protect Lamar, run the ball, play solid
defense on the field, which uh I'm
confident we will do. Uh and then I
think the second thing is just to stay
relentless about you know our fan
experience or game day experience and
our fan engagement overall. That's
really the the second most important
thing that we can do. There's a lot of
technology coming. Our stadium
renovations are really exciting. We're
going to roll out the third phase of
those which we're we're super excited
about here uh you know in the next
several months. And so I think just all
of those opportunities, a new coaching
staff here, that's going to be exciting
uh with the team that's really compete
for championships. So it's an exciting
time to be the Ravens, to be I think in
the in the flock, the fan base of the
Ravens. Um and now we just need to
continue to capitalize and continue to
push ourselves towards championship on
the field. Uh and then in the stadium as
well.
>> Well, you mentioned the stadium. that
has been a major project that has been
ongoing here for for the last few years
and and like you said, this year we get
to kind of put a bow on it and unveil
all these great new spaces that are
going to come to completion. What has
you most excited about the completion of
this project and what it's going to mean
for our stadium?
>> I think the transformation
and the unveiling of the new stadium in
amalgamation of all the projects. So,
you know, we added some premium which is
important, but majority of what we've
done and invested in has been the GA
experience. The every fan that comes in
the stadium is going to have a bunch of
new spaces and opportunities to engage
and activate with their friends with us
uh around the stadium, whether that's
upper concourse and some of the things
that you'll see rolled out there with
the bump out of thousands of new square
footage. um you know, protection from
precipitation and cold, uh more
bathrooms, cut those lines down, new
points of sale, uh concessions so people
aren't standing in line, they can get
back to their seats. But then a plaza,
right, that brings all of that
traditional Baltimore tailgate activity
and energy on game day uh into our plaza
and get that connectivity, that energy
going really early. Uh we're really
excited about technology that's going to
really be interlaid throughout the
entire stadium uh to give people a more
dynamic experience uh and be able to
sound and and mostly uh visual
opportunity to stay connected to the
game uh when you are in the concourses
outside of your seats. So, you know,
it's been a a long project, as you said,
a lot of great planning from our staff
and and I want to shout out Rich Tomio
and Brad DS and a bunch of others that
have put in just an extraordinary amount
of effort. And and I'd be remiss if I
didn't uh thank the folks down in
Annapolis for the trust that they put
into us uh to to renovate the stadium
along with the Maryland Stadium
Authority and our partnership there.
Something that stands out to me is of
course there's Ravens game day and you
just talked through that and that's
going to be just just changing in such a
big way for our game day experience. But
all of these renovations have also
helped open up the stadium beyond
Sundays and Mondays for Ravens football
on Thursdays but throughout the entire
year. We just had the DC United Inner
Miami game with Messi in Baltimore
Morgan Wallen concerts this summer. We
have the All Blacks for South Africa
game coming up this fall. So, you have
all these major events that are coming
to Baltimore. What What does it mean to
have a list of events coming to our city
and our stadium?
>> You know, as one of the objectives,
we tend to not pat ourselves on the
back, pound our our chest too much, but
it is not uncommon when we go to meet
opposing ownership and greet them down
on the field pregame that they really
are complimentary of just the bones and
the way that we've kept up MNT Bank
Stadium. again partnership with the
Stadium Authority of Maryland, the state
and and the Ravens. Steve's been very
generous allowing us to invest uh
upwards of $300 million into the stadium
beyond what we're required to do under
the the uh lease with with the state.
So, we've been forward investors and I
think it shows. So, the stadium's in in
great shape. Then you get an opportunity
to say, okay, with the state, how do we
reinvest to make sure that MNT Bank
Stadium and the Orioles are doing the
same at uh Oral Park. How do we make
sure that our stadium maintains its
status as one of the best in the league?
And with the bones in place and upwards
of $400 plus million dollars of
investment, we have maintained, I think,
the integrity of the design and the feel
and the culture of Mnt Bank Stadium
while really adding some fantastic
proven uh opportunities for fans to
engage and watch the game in different
ways from different places being greater
proximity, but also just to bring more
of a game day experience and a festive
kind of atmosphere to the stadium. So,
we're really excited about all of that.
I think at the end of the day, uh, what
that means is we can go out to promoters
who are looking to bring iconic global
events like All Blacks versus South
Africa, uh, to a stadium like ours
because when they come in and they see
things that they just haven't seen in
another environment, we're still one of
the few outdoor stadiums that has all
the the premium opportunities, but then
the technology engaged and fan
activation areas uh, that are at the
forefront of what the stadium experience
is today. It's allowed us to bring more
and more events and we're excited. A
historic number, six nights this year of
non-Ravens events to the stadium. We're
going to continue to try to pursue and
sustain if not grow that moving forward.
Uh and the renovations were a huge piece
of that um and the vision around that.
And that's what we talked to Governor
Hogan, Governor Moore, and their
administrations about. That's really
important for us to deliver to Mayor
Scott uh more events, major events, bowl
events to downtown Baltimore.
>> It's exciting. It's there's going to be
a lot of fun events there. Another
important piece of of news here coming
out of the owners meetings was the BV1
vote uh which allowed the Ravens to now
market in the territories uh south of us
Prince George's County and Montgomery
County. Uh and this has been an ongoing
conversation uh but it passed here at
league meetings. What's the significance
of this and and what does this mean for
the Ravens?
>> Yeah, let me start with a little history
if that's okay. So, you know, when the
NFL constitution and bylaws were passed,
there was always a diving of rights.
What could the leagues do? What could
the clubs do? Visav the league, visa v
each other. And BV1 is the provision
that largely govern the rights between
the clubs and the leagues. There was a
special provision in BV1 for any teams
that were in really close proximity to
each other to say, okay, this is how
we're going to divvy up the rights.
That's probably a little bit of a
regressive uh way of thinking about the
world now that we have the internet and
social media and all these different
things. The way we engage with fans,
fanhood is no longer so geographic. Uh
BV1 expired on its natural terms or was
set to expire tomorrow. Today we had a
vote to extend but also evolve BV1. And
one of the places we wanted to take as a
league a close look was how do two
stadiums that are 30 miles apart really
think about the territory that lies in
between them. And I think we got to a
good point with Montgomery and PG County
that are in really close proximity both
less than 20 miles from our stadium
whereas before we were restricted in
certain ways from being able to activate
in those areas. So when we looked at it
with the league and the entire body of
ownership uh the thought was to evolve
it. Now that we're we're sharing those
markets uh in Montgomery County and PG
County, we're excited about that. We
have hundreds of thousands of Ravens
fans uh across uh Montgomery, PG County,
and of course, Northern Virginia and DC,
just as the Commanders have uh a number
of fans in the the Baltimore territory,
so to speak. But this was a good uh
landing spot for us to evolve and to be
able to activate uh both uh with with
fans and allow some of our partners to
activate in those two counties,
important counties to us and where we
have a ton of members of the flock.
>> Yeah, no doubt. Something that will be
re relevant in those counties and also
in Baltimore is the continued work that
we do in the community. This past year
we had some major legacy projects that
we rolled out the Hilton Rec Center uh
which was really big. just most recently
a few weeks ago partnering with College
Track to open the Baltimore Ravens
College Track Center in Baltimore. These
are these are major projects that are
going to have a big impact on the
community. Why is that such a big focus
and initiative, a continued focus for
this organization?
>> It comes from Stephen Renee. You know,
they're so philanthropic and giving and
they're committed to it. It's really
part of, I think, their faith and their
belief system and they want the
organization to reflect that. So, when
you look at our mission, it's right
there. win games, amaze our fans, impact
the community in a positive way. You
asked earlier, uh, you know, what's most
important for us to focus on, and I said
winning and fans. Uh, but in line with
that, you know, one of the things that I
think I'm most proud of here is to with
our entire staff really dive in in a
serious deep way, uh, in a rich way how
we impact the community in some of our
community work. And Steve really
challenged us. He said, you know, you
all do a lot high volume of events. Can
we find some things that will have
legacy deep impact and you talked about
our two, you know, kind of crown jewel
projects. One in the Hilton Community
Center, uh, with Boys and Girls Club,
the Ravens Boys and Girls Club, uh,
which is going to be a fantastic and
already is, but is going to continue to
be a fantastic for decades space for
kids after school in the that community
in West Baltimore. And then the second
is our Ravens college access program
which is a $50 million commitment over
10 years bridges collegebound now the
Baltimore Ravens college track facility
which we just opened a couple weeks ago
touching thousands of kids uh across
Baltimore and helping them find their
way to prepare to go to college, get
into school and then um you know be
successful once you get into school.
Most of these kids are firstgen students
and we have made it extraordinarily
uh difficult to navigate getting into
college, having success college and then
getting out, you know, with with great
jobs. And all three of these programs
and their leadership uh are proven, have
great track records, uh and it's a way
for us to give back to youth and
education. And we feel like education's
tremendously transformative and we're
huge believers in the youth of our city.
I want to bring it back to the field for
a minute. You mentioned the coaching
staff. It's not just Jesse and that's
been the big focus, but there's it's all
new coaches. We see it every day in the
building. You're getting to know uh
people who are coming to the building
for the first time and it's it's been a
massive change.
>> How is that? We feel the energy, you
know, when seeing it every day that it's
just it's it's people who are coming in
and looking to build something and
there's just this energy and excitement.
How have you seen uh the energy factor
with this new coaching staff? Yeah,
they're they're to a to a coach really
positive, engaging, really bringing
fresh ideas, working well together. I
I'm really excited when the players get
back uh to see the interaction between
the staff and and some of our players
and the leadership in particular and how
they ingrained. But Jess is available.
Uh he's they're they're present and uh
it's been, as you said, just a lift in
the building. really refreshing to have
uh some young energy and new ideas
around. Uh and that's with all due
respect obviously to a tremendous staff
that was here before. Uh but we're
really excited about what uh what is to
come and we'll start to see it roll out
this spring in a couple weeks.
>> No doubt. You one new hire that you made
this year connected to coaching but a
little bit different is Dr. Nick Gil
who's going to be over uh the entire
performance operation. And he comes from
just so fans know he comes from New
Zealand. He was with the All Blacks
there previously and and now he's coming
here to Baltimore. I'm curious what went
into that hire, how did that come about?
How did he come on your radar and and
ultimately uh what made this decision to
bring him in and oversee that unit?
>> Yeah, both both Eric and I for some time
uh have looked around sport uh and
noticed some things that we saw, learned
uh and and exposed ourselves to best
practices in global sport. And there are
some places where I think we've we've
both felt like we could get better on
the performance side of medical.
Traditionally, those two um functions
sit on different sides of the building,
report differently. And you know,
there's a high performance model that
we've seen elsewhere that we're going to
in integrate here. And Nick is a guy
who's been really successful for a long
period of time was looking for a
challenge. Uh I had been in contact with
him and some others you know at the uh
elite level of of high performance
models combining medical and
performance. Uh Eric had some folks that
he understood and we went through an
interview process and we're really uh
impressed with Nick and we're excited
about what he'll bring to the table to
help us get better every day. And uh I
think he's going to help us
tremendously. I'm really excited to get
him here in the building and I think
just a couple days.
>> Yeah. Well, him and the players are
coming back and in the last one as you
mentioned the players are going to be
back. We're all we all feel that energy
and the excitement when they're in the
building and and you talked about Jesse
and the the expectations as players come
back and you look at this season, you
look at the steps leading into this
year.
>> What are the expectations, you know, for
this season uh with a new head coach and
and the championship aspirations that
that exist? Uh but as everyone comes
back into the building, you look ahead
to the season, what are the
expectations?
>> Still still blood in the mouth from
Pittsburgh. uh you know, so so
absolutely eager to get back uh onto the
field and and chase another Super Bowl
this year. Uh I know to a to a player in
that locker room, everyone feels like uh
they're ready to to get back after it.
And uh we left with that bad taste in
your mouth, which you normally do, but
that one was particularly tough to take.
So I know guys want to turn that back
around and they're going to be eager to
learn the new system and get get after
it. Uh, I would say, you know, from my
perspective as I look at the 2026
season, I mean, we don't want to put too
much pressure on Jess, but we've got a
MVP caliber, uh, quarterback,
star-studded defense, and we've added a
guy like Trey, you know, to our pass
rush. We think that's going to help us.
Uh, we've got a couple picks here high
that we're eager to deploy and bring
some folks in that can help us as well.
You know, how well we've coached and
developed. that's going to be a hallmark
of what we do continually. So, uh, we're
not lowering our standards. At the same
time, we're going to be realistic about
it, but really excited to see Declan and
Jesse get to work crafting this defense
with Weave. Uh, so it's going to be
exciting, exciting spring, and I know
the players are eager to get going.
>> Well, we can't wait, Sashi. Appreciate
the time. Thank you so much.
>> Always.
>> You're listening to the Lounge Podcast.
We're coming to you from the SeatGeek
studio. We want to mention our partners
at DraftKings Sportsbook. They are an
official sports betting partner of the
Baltimore Ravens, DraftKings Sportsbook,
The Crown is yours. So, Cliff, obviously
just uh had a chance to talk with Sashi
a little bit ago. Uh what stood out to
you in hearing from him about his vision
uh for this team and this organization?
>> I think it's an exciting time for the
organization. Obviously, it's been an
off season of change. You know, we have
the coaching change, new staff in the
building. Sashi excited about that. The
renovations to the stadium and then the
whole outlook for the 2026 season. It's
just, you know, the Ravens have been
established as one of the league's
marquee franchises and that is
continuing, but there's always change
and evolution and, you know, Sashi has a
vision, this organization has a vision
for what it wants to accomplish on the
field and what it wants to mean, what it
wants to mean to the community in
Baltimore. So hearing Sashi talk about
both of those things, merging them
together, it's really interesting. And
you know, it's exciting to see what's
going to develop both with the stadium
and then on the field and also the
Ravens impact in Baltimore.
>> Yeah, it's I mean, he said it when I
asked him about top priorities, winning
and that's something that will always be
the case is remains unchanged and
there's a commitment to that. There's a
commitment to how the Ravens spend.
There's a commitment to the investment
the Ravens make in the in the Underarm
Performance Center in in Emity Bay
Stadium, in the players overall. And so
there's all of it is about looking for
ways to improve. And I looking at the
stadium real quick, like I I'm excited
about this roll out of the renovations.
This has been a multi-year project,
hundreds of millions of dollars invested
in this space, and we've seen the first
two phases of it. And I think that this
phase, this final one where it all kind
of gets brought to completion, is just
going to be awesome for fans. It's going
to be a way for everybody to engage with
this team, change the way that you do
game day to a certain extent, and I
think that fans are going to love it.
Yeah, I mean Mnt Bank Stadium has always
been a great place to go see the Ravens
play. The Ravens flock is a great fan
base. And then the third piece is having
a great team on the field. So when you
think about, you know, the atmosphere at
the stadium, night games, some of the
electrifying moments we've had there
over the years to have it in a stadium
that looks, you know, picture perfect
and then have a new coaching staff and
exciting players on the field. Hopefully
it all will come together. That's the
vision. And yes, after last season,
Sashi talked about, you know, the
organization has a bad tasting about the
players do after the way it ended, but
they have the team to turn it around
immediately. So, there's a lot to be
excited about as we look forward to
what's going to be on the field next
season.
>> Yeah, I think that something we've said
many times is the Ravens turn over every
stone looking for ways to get better.
They do that with the the the process
going through the draft. They do that
with player evaluation. They do that
with the way that they invest in the
performance aspect of things. they're
doing it at the stadium. Like every
possible way uh that they can find ways
to improve, they do it. And I think
we've seen that this offseason clearly
uh with the hiring of Jesse Mentor and
the coaching staff and some of the
investments the Ravens have made. And I
think all of that should should I think
the team is going to be in really good
position. Like players are going to be
back in the building soon. They're going
to be back in the building in a couple
of weeks. And there's just going to be
this energy and this excitement uh
actually next week. They're going to be
back in the building next week. And like
there there's gonna be this energy and
excitement with having them there. And I
think that uh this team is going to hit
the ground running. Like there's a long
way between now and football season, but
like I I just like for all those
reasons, I think that I could not be
more fired up about this upcoming
season.
>> Yeah. Si touched on it. This team is
hungry. Uh he's already sensing, you
know, speaking to players, the attitude
that the players are going to be hungry
to get back in the building and get to
work. And then that is to me accelerated
with a new coach. Every player knows
they kind of have a fresh start whether
they need it or not that they have to
leave an impression on now a new
coaching staff. And I think that's kind
of a natural source of motivation. So
with the coaches being excited, the
players and the team knowing that they
have the talent to do something special.
I mean, for Jesse Mentor, it's great as
a first year head coach to go into a
situation where the culture is used to
winning and you have players that you
can win with right away. So, again, you
know, the clock keeps moving, players
are almost here and then when they come,
I think the energy in the building is
going to pick up even more.
>> Yeah, no doubt. So, we can't wait for
that. It's been a good week here at the
uh league meetings. A lot of business uh
getting done and it's it's exciting to
know what's on the horizon. So, uh, as
always, you can email us at the lounge
ravens.nl.net.
Send in those emails. Uh, thank you so
much for listening and watching, and
we'll be back with you again soon.